<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Robert Douglas Ferguson</title>
    <link href="http://www.robertdouglasferguson.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="http://www.robertdouglasferguson.com" />
    <updated>2021-09-15T12:13:45-04:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Robert</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.robertdouglasferguson.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Bio</title>
        <author>
            <name>Robert</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://www.robertdouglasferguson.com/robert-douglas-ferguson.html"/>
        <id>http://www.robertdouglasferguson.com/robert-douglas-ferguson.html</id>

        <updated>2021-09-15T11:57:18-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    I am a doctoral candidate at the McGill School of Information Studies in Montréal, Québec, Canada. My Ph.D research explores personal information management (PIM) and personal archiving. I am interested in the relationship between records management and financial behaviours among young adults. My current research aims to improve&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>I am a doctoral candidate at the <a title="McGill School of Information Studies" href="http://www.mcgill.ca/sis/school-information-studies-1" target="_blank" rel="noopener">McGill School of Information Studies</a> in Montréal, Québec, Canada. My <a title="Participate!" href="http://www.robertdouglasferguson.com/participate/">Ph.D research</a> explores personal information management (PIM) and personal archiving. I am interested in the relationship between records management and financial behaviours among young adults. My current research aims to improve the recordkeeping capacities of financial tools and services. My doctoral research is supervised by <a title="France Bouthillier" href="http://www.mcgill.ca/sis/people/faculty/moffatt" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Prof. Karyn Moffatt Ph.D</a> at the McGill School of Information Studies. This project is funded by the <a href="http://sshrc-crsh.gc.ca" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Social Science and Humanities Research Council of Canada (SSHRC)</a>.</p>
<figure class="post__image post__image--right"><img loading="lazy"  src="http://www.robertdouglasferguson.com/media/posts/1/mcgillschoolofinformationstudies_studentlaptopwindow-small-300x125-3.png" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="http://www.robertdouglasferguson.com/media/posts/1/responsive/mcgillschoolofinformationstudies_studentlaptopwindow-small-300x125-3-xs.png 300w ,http://www.robertdouglasferguson.com/media/posts/1/responsive/mcgillschoolofinformationstudies_studentlaptopwindow-small-300x125-3-sm.png 480w ,http://www.robertdouglasferguson.com/media/posts/1/responsive/mcgillschoolofinformationstudies_studentlaptopwindow-small-300x125-3-md.png 768w ,http://www.robertdouglasferguson.com/media/posts/1/responsive/mcgillschoolofinformationstudies_studentlaptopwindow-small-300x125-3-lg.png 1024w ,http://www.robertdouglasferguson.com/media/posts/1/responsive/mcgillschoolofinformationstudies_studentlaptopwindow-small-300x125-3-xl.png 1360w ,http://www.robertdouglasferguson.com/media/posts/1/responsive/mcgillschoolofinformationstudies_studentlaptopwindow-small-300x125-3-2xl.png 1600w"  alt="bio pic 1" width="300" height="125"></figure>
<p>I hold Masters and Bachelors of Arts degrees in Social Anthropology from <a title="York University" href="http://www.yorku.ca/laps/anth/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">York University</a> in Toronto, Ontario, Canada<span style="color: var(--text-editor-body-color); font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">. My MA </span><span style="color: var(--text-editor-body-color); font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">research explored member attitudes towards online research ethics and the data-mining of personal health information on the patient social networking website PatientsLikeMe.com. My masters research was supervised by </span><a title="Naomi Adelson" href="http://www.yorku.ca/laps/anth/faculty/adelson/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener" style="font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">Prof. Naomi Adelson Ph.D</a><span style="color: var(--text-editor-body-color); font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);"> (York University). As an anthropologist by training, I am interested in individual and group identity construction through documentation and information-related practices.</span></p>
<figure class="post__image post__image--right"><img loading="lazy"  src="http://www.robertdouglasferguson.com/media/posts/1/photo-6-small-300x224-2.jpg" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="http://www.robertdouglasferguson.com/media/posts/1/responsive/photo-6-small-300x224-2-xs.jpg 300w ,http://www.robertdouglasferguson.com/media/posts/1/responsive/photo-6-small-300x224-2-sm.jpg 480w ,http://www.robertdouglasferguson.com/media/posts/1/responsive/photo-6-small-300x224-2-md.jpg 768w ,http://www.robertdouglasferguson.com/media/posts/1/responsive/photo-6-small-300x224-2-lg.jpg 1024w ,http://www.robertdouglasferguson.com/media/posts/1/responsive/photo-6-small-300x224-2-xl.jpg 1360w ,http://www.robertdouglasferguson.com/media/posts/1/responsive/photo-6-small-300x224-2-2xl.jpg 1600w"  alt="bio pic 2" width="300" height="224"></figure>
<p>I am part of the <a href="http://act.mcgill.ca" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Accessible Computing Technologies Research Group (ACT)</a> at McGill University. Our current project explores information behaviours and needs of family, friends, and caregivers of loved-ones in hospice and palliative care. Our aim is to develop technologies enhance telepresence, communication, and social support at the end-of-life.</p>
<p>I am a student member of the <a href="http://asist.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Association of Information Science and Technology (ASIS&amp;T)</a> and the <a href="http://www.acm.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Association for Computing Machinery (ACM)</a>. I serve as the 2014-2015 secretary of the <a href="http://www.mcgill.ca/sis-students/asist" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ASIS&amp;T McGill Student Chapter</a>. I have presented research and participated in workshops at <a href="http://cscw.acm.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Computer Supported Collaborative Work (CSCW)</a>, <a href="http://www.sigchi.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Computer Humans Interactions (CHI)</a>, GRAND NCE/Canada 3.0, Web 2.U, Congress on Whole Person Care, and the annual meeting of Association of Information Science and Technology.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Publications</title>
        <author>
            <name>Robert</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://www.robertdouglasferguson.com/publications.html"/>
        <id>http://www.robertdouglasferguson.com/publications.html</id>

        <updated>2021-09-09T16:20:29-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Journal Articles Ferguson, R., Crist, E., and Moffatt, K. (2017). A framework for negotiating ethics in sensitive settings: Hospice as a case study. Interacting with Computers, Special Issues on Co-Constructing Meaning: Ethics Matter(s) in Design Research, 29(1):10–26. doi: 10.1093/iwc/iww018 Ferguson, R. (2017). Negotiating Consent, Compensation,&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <h3>Journal Articles</h3>
<p>Ferguson, R., Crist, E., and Moffatt, K. (2017). A framework for negotiating ethics in sensitive settings: Hospice as a case study. Interacting with Computers, Special Issues on Co-Constructing Meaning: Ethics Matter(s) in Design Research, 29(1):10–26. doi: 10.1093/iwc/iww018</p>
<h3>Book Chapters</h3>
<p>Ferguson, R. (2017). Negotiating Consent, Compensation, and Privacy in Internet Research: PatientsLikeMe.com as a Case Study. In K. Kinder-Kurlanda, K. &amp; M. Zimmer (Eds.), Internet Research Ethics for the Social Age: New Challenges, Cases, and Contexts. Switzerland: Peter Lang.</p>
<h3>Refereed Papers in Archival Conference Proceedings</h3>
<p>Ferguson, R., Massimi, M. Crist, E., and Moffatt, K. (2014). Craving, Creating, and Constructing Comfort: Insights and Opportunities for Technology in Hospice. Proceedings of the 17th ACM Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work &amp; Social Computing (CSCW 2014), 1479–1490. [ACM CSCW Best paper award]</p>
<h3>Workshop Proceedings</h3>
<p>Ferguson, R. (2016). Ethics and the Long-Term Management of Personal Information. Position paper presented at Personal Information Management Workshop 2016 at ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI 2016), May 7-8, San Jose, California.</p>
<p>Ferguson, R. (2014). Getting Personal: Bereavement Interviewing and Intervening. Position paper presented at Workshop, Co-creating &amp; Identity-Making in CSCW: Revisiting Ethics in Design Research at the ACM Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work &amp; Social Computing (CSCW 2014), Feb 16, 2014, Baltimore, Maryland.</p>
<p>Ferguson, R. (2013). An Anthropological Approach to Personal Information Management, Position paper presented at Personal Information Management Workshop 2013: Beyond the Cloud: Rethinking Information Boundaries. Annual Meeting of the Association of Information Science and Technology (ASIS&amp;T), Nov 1, Montréal, Québec.</p>
<p>Ferguson, R. (2013). Using the Information Senses Framework to Think About Patient-Centered Biomedical Recordkeeping. Position paper presented at Beyond Formality: Informal Communication In Health Practices Workshop at the ACM Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work &amp; Social Computing (CSCW 2013), Feb 24, San Antonio, Texas.</p>
<p>Ferguson, R., Moffatt, K., and Massimi, M. (2013). Formal and informal messages: Early reflections on how context and content influence ICT use at the end-of-life. Position paper presented at Beyond Formality: Informal Communication in Health Practices Workshop at the ACM Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work &amp; Social Computing (CSCW 2013) Feb 24, San Antonio, Texas.</p>
<h6>Conference Extended Abstracts, Posters, and Demos</h6>
<p>Ferguson, R., Massimi, M., Crist, E., and Moffatt, K. (2013). Supporting communication at the end-of-life: Comparing ICT use by families in hospice settings. Poster presentation at the Annual General Meeting of the Graphics, Animation and New media (GRAND) Network of Centers of Excellence, (GRAND 2013), Toronto, Ontario.</p>
<p>Ferguson, R. (2013). The Information Senses of Whole Person Care: A PatientsLIkeMe.com Case Study. Poster presentation at First World Congress on Whole Person Care, Montréal, Québec.</p>
<p>Ferguson, R. (2013). Exploring Emergent Research Ethics and Attitudes Towards Privacy on PatientsLikeMe.com. Poster Presentation at Social Media and Society 2013, Halifax, Nova Scotia.</p>
<p>Ferguson, R. (2012). What Does Your Username and Picture Mean/Come From?, Serendipitous Identity Discovery when Data-Mining Personal Health Information, Poster Presentation at SCORE: Serendipity, Chance and Opportunity in Information Discovery Workshop. Montréal, Québec.</p>
<h3>Theses</h3>
<p>Ferguson, R. D. (Forthcoming). Exploring Personal Financial Information Management Among Young Adults. (Unpublished doctoral dissertation). McGill University, Montréal, Quebec.</p>
<p>Ferguson, R. D. (2011). Crowdsourcing health information: An ethnographic exploration of public and private health information on patientslikeme.com. (Unpublished master’s thesis). York University, Toronto, Ontario.</p>
<h3>Presentations and Talks</h3>
<p>Dorey, J., &amp; Ferguson, R. (2017). Research ethics and protecting your research participants Workshop at Archival Education Research Institute (AERI 2017). Toronto, Ontario.</p>
<p>Ferguson, R. (2017). Exploring the personal financial information management of young adults. Personal Digital Archiving 2017 (Palo Alto, California).</p>
<p>Ferguson, R. (2015). In Interfaces We Trust? Exploring Preservation of Personal Financial Information Among Young Adults. Archival Education Research Institute (AERI 2015). College Park, Maryland.</p>
<p>Ferguson R. (2013). From expectation to reality: an exploration of patients’ perspectives on reciprocity and fair use of data within Patientslikeme.com. 6th Annual Web2.U Symposium. Montréal, Québec.</p>
<p>Ferguson, R. (2009). Campus Friction: An Ethnographic Exploration of Protest in Vari Hall, Playing the Field Conference. Toronto, Ontario.</p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Contact</title>
        <author>
            <name>Robert</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://www.robertdouglasferguson.com/contact.html"/>
        <id>http://www.robertdouglasferguson.com/contact.html</id>

        <updated>2021-09-09T16:19:06-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Email: fergusonrobertdouglas [at] gmail [dot] com I respond to most emails within 24-48 hours of receipt. Please check your spam or junk folder in the event that you do not hear from us within that timeframe. Robert Douglas Ferguson School of Information Studies McGill University 3661&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <h3 style="text-align: left;" align="center">Email:</h3>
<p style="text-align: left;" align="center">fergusonrobertdouglas [at] gmail [dot] com</p>
<p style="text-align: left;" align="center"><em>I respond to most emails within 24-48 hours of receipt. Please check your spam or junk folder in the event that you do not hear from us within that timeframe.</em></p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;" align="center">Office Location and Mailing:</h3>
<p>Robert Douglas Ferguson</p>
<p>School of Information Studies <br><span style="line-height: 1.5;">McGill University <br></span><span style="line-height: 1.5;">3661 Rue Peel </span><span style="line-height: 1.5;">Montréal, <br></span><span style="line-height: 1.5;">Québec <br></span><span style="line-height: 1.5;">H3A 1X1</span></p>
<p><em>(Office Hours: By Appointment.)</em></p>
<p style="text-align: left;" align="center"><div class="post__iframe"><iframe loading="lazy" width="400" height="300" style="border: 0;" src="https://www.google.com/maps/embed?pb=!1m14!1m8!1m3!1d22370.464449562267!2d-73.580253!3d45.503877!3m2!1i1024!2i768!4f13.1!3m3!1m2!1s0x4cc91a38e9fe89bd%3A0x761acfcfdf462944!2s3661+Rue+Peel%2C+McGill+University%2C+Montr%C3%A9al%2C+QC+H3A+1X1%2C+Canada!5e0!3m2!1sen!2sus!4v1422476249671" frameborder="0"></iframe></div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Research</title>
        <author>
            <name>Robert</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://www.robertdouglasferguson.com/research.html"/>
        <id>http://www.robertdouglasferguson.com/research.html</id>

        <updated>2021-09-09T16:19:29-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Doctoral Research Exploring Personal Financial Information Management Among Young Adults Financial experts express concerns that young adults exhibit poor financial habits. Poor financial habits can manifest in a vary of ways, such as high levels of credit card debt, low levels of saving, and difficulty&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <h3>Doctoral Research</h3>
<p><em>Exploring Personal Financial Information Management Among Young Adults</em></p>
<p>Financial experts express concerns that young adults exhibit poor financial habits. Poor financial habits can manifest in a vary of ways, such as high levels of credit card debt, low levels of saving, and difficulty creating or sticking to a budget. As a result, there is an explosion of educational and technological resources being developed specifically for young adults with the aim to increase their financial literacy and instill good financial behaviours earlier in life. Yet, many of these resources provide sparse instruction on how to manage the documentation associated with personal finance. This doctoral research project attempts to answer the following research questions: (1) what records and supporting documents do the personal collections of financial information of young adults typically contain?; (2) how do young adults “manage” their collections of personal financial information within a personal space of information?; and (3) what are the incentives, goals, tasks, and other factors that motivate the management of personal financial information among young adults? And why? This project aims to conduct approximately 40 guided-tour interviews with young adults (ages 18-25) in the Montreal area. Interviews will be structured using Cognitive-Work Analysis (CWA) and the theoretical framework of Human-Information Interactions (HII). Data analysis will use qualitative techniques inspired by grounded-theory. The anticipate outcomes of this research are a description of the actual contents of personal collections of financial information by young adults, an analysis of the processes and information behaviours associated with curation and exploitation of a personal collection of financial information, and an analysis of the environmental and personal factors that motivates personal financial information management among young adults. This project is funded by the Social Science and Humanities Research Council of Canada (SSHRC).</p>
<h3><a title="Accessible Computing Technologies Research Group" href="http://act.mcgill.ca/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Accessible Computing Technologies Research Group</a></h3>
<p><em>Supporting Coordination and Communication During Hospice Care </em></p>
<p>Staying connected is a primary concern of hospice and palliative care patients and their families, but managing and coordinating interaction to best meet the varying needs and capabilities of patients is challenging. This project explores this space, with the long-term goal of addressing both patient and family needs and designing information technologies that enhance telepresence and communication between families and friends at the end of life. In this project, I was responsible for participant recruitment, data collection, and qualitative analysis of the data set.</p>
<p><em>Digital Paper-Based Communication Systems</em></p>
<p>This project explores the use of digital pens and paper as a platform for blending the aesthics of handwritten letters with the convenience of e-mail. In this project, I was responsible for data collection and qualitative analysis of the data set.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>CV</title>
        <author>
            <name>Robert</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://www.robertdouglasferguson.com/cv.html"/>
        <id>http://www.robertdouglasferguson.com/cv.html</id>

        <updated>2021-09-15T12:13:45-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Education Ph.D., Information Studies, In Progress Supervisor: Karyn Moffatt Ph.D. School of Information Studies McGill University, Montréal, Canada Dissertation Title: Exploring Personal Financial Information Management Among Young Adults M.A., Social Anthropology, 2011 Supervisor: Naomi Adelson Ph.D. Department of Anthropology York University, Toronto, Canada Thesis Title:&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <h3>Education</h3>
<p>Ph.D., Information Studies, In Progress Supervisor: Karyn Moffatt Ph.D. School of Information Studies McGill University, Montréal, Canada</p>
<p>Dissertation Title: Exploring Personal Financial Information Management Among Young Adults</p>
<p>M.A., Social Anthropology, 2011 Supervisor: Naomi Adelson Ph.D. Department of Anthropology York University, Toronto, Canada</p>
<p>Thesis Title: Crowdsourcing health information: An ethnographic exploration of public and private health information on patientslikeme.com</p>
<h3>Scholarships and Awards</h3>
<h6>Scholarships</h6>
<h6>External (Federal)</h6>
<p>Doctoral Fellowship, 2015-17 Social Sciences and Humanities Research Council of Canada (SSHRC), $40,000 24 months</p>
<h6>Internal (University)</h6>
<p>Doctoral Fellowship, 2011-12 Tim Casgrain Fellowship in Information Studies, $20000 12 months</p>
<h3>Awards</h3>
<h6>Merit</h6>
<p>Best Paper Award ACM Computer Supported Collaborative Work (CSCW) Title: Craving, Creating, and Constructing Comfort: Insights and Opportunities for Technology in Hospice 2014 Award Vivi Martin Fellowship in Information Studies $1500, 2012-13 Award John A. Price Fieldwork Award, York University $500, 2010-11 Distinction Vanier College Peer Advising, York University, 2009-10</p>
<h6>Travel</h6>
<p>Travel Award Dorothy Carruthers Prize in Archival Studies $1000, 2016-17 Travel Award Graduate Excellence Award in Information Studies $485, 2016-17 Travel Award Dorothy Carruthers Prize in Archival Studies $1000, 2015-16 Travel Award Graduate Excellence Award in Arts $2000, 2015-16 Travel Award Social Sciences and Humanities Research Council of Canada $502, 2014-15 Travel Award School of Information Studies Award $500, 2013-14 Travel Award Social Sciences and Humanities Research Council of Canada $675, 2012-13</p>
<h3>Publications</h3>
<h6>Journal Articles</h6>
<p>Ferguson, R., Crist, E., and Moffatt, K. (2017). A framework for negotiating ethics in sensitive settings: Hospice as a case study. Interacting with Computers, Special Issues on Co-Constructing Meaning: Ethics Matter(s) in Design Research, 29(1):10–26. doi: 10.1093/iwc/iww018</p>
<h6>Book Chapters</h6>
<p>Ferguson, R. (2017). Negotiating Consent, Compensation, and Privacy in Internet Research: PatientsLikeMe.com as a Case Study. In K. Kinder-Kurlanda, K. &amp; M. Zimmer (Eds.), Internet Research Ethics for the Social Age: New Challenges, Cases, and Contexts. Switzerland: Peter Lang.</p>
<h6>Refereed Papers in Archival Conference Proceedings</h6>
<p>Ferguson, R., Massimi, M. Crist, E., and Moffatt, K. (2014). Craving, Creating, and Constructing Comfort: Insights and Opportunities for Technology in Hospice. Proceedings of the 17th ACM Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work &amp; Social Computing (CSCW 2014), 1479–1490. [ACM CSCW Best paper award]</p>
<h6>Workshop Proceedings</h6>
<p>Ferguson, R. (2016). Ethics and the Long-Term Management of Personal Information. Position paper presented at Personal Information Management Workshop 2016 at ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI 2016), May 7-8, San Jose, California.</p>
<p>Ferguson, R. (2014). Getting Personal: Bereavement Interviewing and Intervening. Position paper presented at Workshop, Co-creating &amp; Identity-Making in CSCW: Revisiting Ethics in Design Research at the ACM Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work &amp; Social Computing (CSCW 2014), Feb 16, 2014, Baltimore, Maryland.</p>
<p>Ferguson, R. (2013). An Anthropological Approach to Personal Information Management, Position paper presented at Personal Information Management Workshop 2013: Beyond the Cloud: Rethinking Information Boundaries. Annual Meeting of the Association of Information Science and Technology (ASIS&amp;T), Nov 1, Montréal, Québec.</p>
<p>Ferguson, R. (2013). Using the Information Senses Framework to Think About Patient-Centered Biomedical Recordkeeping. Position paper presented at Beyond Formality: Informal Communication In Health Practices Workshop at the ACM Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work &amp; Social Computing (CSCW 2013), Feb 24, San Antonio, Texas.</p>
<p>Ferguson, R., Moffatt, K., and Massimi, M. (2013). Formal and informal messages: Early reflections on how context and content influence ICT use at the end-of-life. Position paper presented at Beyond Formality: Informal Communication in Health Practices Workshop at the ACM Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work &amp; Social Computing (CSCW 2013) Feb 24, San Antonio, Texas.</p>
<h6>Conference Extended Abstracts, Posters, and Demos</h6>
<p>Ferguson, R., Massimi, M., Crist, E., and Moffatt, K. (2013). Supporting communication at the end-of-life: Comparing ICT use by families in hospice settings. Poster presentation at the Annual General Meeting of the Graphics, Animation and New media (GRAND) Network of Centers of Excellence, (GRAND 2013), Toronto, Ontario.</p>
<p>Ferguson, R. (2013). The Information Senses of Whole Person Care: A PatientsLIkeMe.com Case Study. Poster presentation at First World Congress on Whole Person Care, Montréal, Québec.</p>
<p>Ferguson, R. (2013). Exploring Emergent Research Ethics and Attitudes Towards Privacy on PatientsLikeMe.com. Poster Presentation at Social Media and Society 2013, Halifax, Nova Scotia.</p>
<p>Ferguson, R. (2012). What Does Your Username and Picture Mean/Come From?, Serendipitous Identity Discovery when Data-Mining Personal Health Information, Poster Presentation at SCORE: Serendipity, Chance and Opportunity in Information Discovery Workshop. Montréal, Québec.</p>
<h6>Theses</h6>
<p>Ferguson, R. D. (Forthcoming). Exploring Personal Financial Information Management Among Young Adults. (Unpublished doctoral dissertation). McGill University, Montréal, Quebec.</p>
<p>Ferguson, R. D. (2011). Crowdsourcing health information: An ethnographic exploration of public and private health information on patientslikeme.com. (Unpublished master’s thesis). York University, Toronto, Ontario.</p>
<h6>Presentations and Talks</h6>
<p>Dorey, J., &amp; Ferguson, R. (2017). Research ethics and protecting your research participants Workshop at Archival Education Research Institute (AERI 2017). Toronto, Ontario.</p>
<p>Ferguson, R. (2017). Exploring the personal financial information management of young adults. Personal Digital Archiving 2017 (Palo Alto, California).</p>
<p>Ferguson, R. (2015). In Interfaces We Trust? Exploring Preservation of Personal Financial Information Among Young Adults. Archival Education Research Institute (AERI 2015). College Park, Maryland.</p>
<p>Ferguson R. (2013). From expectation to reality: an exploration of patients’ perspectives on reciprocity and fair use of data within Patientslikeme.com. 6th Annual Web2.U Symposium. Montréal, Québec.</p>
<p>Ferguson, R. (2009). Campus Friction: An Ethnographic Exploration of Protest in Vari Hall, Playing the Field Conference. Toronto, Ontario.</p>
<h3>Research and Teaching</h3>
<h6>Research</h6>
<p>Research Assistant, 2011-17 Accessible Computing Technologies Research Group School of Information Studies, McGill University Montréal, Canada</p>
<p>Project Title: Supporting Social Interaction During Hospice</p>
<p>Description: Staying connected is a primary concern of hospice and palliative care patients and their families, but managing and coordinating interaction to best meet the varying needs and capabilities of patients is challenging. Using a series of in-depth semi-structured interviews, this project explores this space, with the long-term goal of developing new technologies that address both patient and family needs.</p>
<p>Project Title: Digital Paper-Based Communication Systems</p>
<p>Description: Using participatory design, this project explores the potential of digital paper and pens as a platform for blending the aesthetics of handwritten letters with the convenience of e-mail for older adults.</p>
<p>Graduate Assistant, 2010 Department of Anthropology, York University Toronto, Canada</p>
<p>Project Title: Social Implications of Space Exploration and Astrobiology Database</p>
<p>Description: The aim of this project is to create a searchable database of resources dedicated to the social science and humanities research that explores the implications of the space exploration and the search for life on other planets.</p>
<h3>Teaching</h3>
<p>Teaching Assistant, 2012-17 School of Information Studies, McGill University Montréal, Québec</p>
<p>GLIS 602 Integrating Research and Practice, 2017 GLIS 611 Research Methods and Analysis, 2013, 2014 GLIS 601 Information and Society, 2012, 2013, 2014</p>
<p>Teaching Assistant, 2011-12 Department of Anthropology, York University Toronto, Canada</p>
<p>ANTH 1110 Introduction to Social Anthropology, 2011</p>
<h3>Service</h3>
<h6>Academic Service</h6>
<p>Reviewer (Conferences), 2014-17 ACM Conference on Computer Supported Collaborative Work (CSCW) ACM Conference on Computer Human Interactions (CHI)</p>
<p>Doctoral Organizing Subcommittee, 2017 Archival Education Research Institute (AERI) Toronto, Canada</p>
<p>Student Volunteer, 2017 ACM CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems Denver, Colorado</p>
<p>Conference Treasurer, 2010 Ethnographic Appetites and Feeding the Senses Conference York University Social Anthropology Graduate’s Association Toronto, Canada</p>
<p>Conference Banquet Coordinator, 2009 Playing the Field Conference York University Social Anthropology Graduate’s Association Toronto, Canada</p>
<h6>University and Departmental Service</h6>
<p>McGill School of Information Studies Cyclical Program Review, 2017 Doctoral Student Representative</p>
<p>Secretary, 2015 Association of Information Science and Technology Montréal Student’s Chapter Montréal, Canada</p>
<p>Interim Communications Officer, 2014 Association of Information Science and Technology Montréal Student’s Chapter Montréal, Canada</p>
<p>Doctoral Program Representative, 2013 McGill Library and Information Studies Student's Association Montréal, Canada</p>
<p>Association Chair, 2010 York University Social Anthropology Graduate’s Association Toronto, Canada</p>
<p>Association Treasurer, 2009 York University Social Anthropology Graduate’s Association Toronto, Canada</p>
<p>Peer Advisor, 2009 Vanier College, York University Toronto, Canada</p>
<h6>Community Service</h6>
<p>Vice-President and Communication Officer, 2015-18 Board of Directors Céu do Montréal, Eclectic Centre for the Universal Flowing Light Montréal, Québec</p>
<p>Archival Technician, 2011-13 Reserves Collection Archives gaies du Québec Montréal, Canada</p>
<h3>Professional Association and Research Consortium Memberships</h3>
<p>Student Member The Association for Information Science and Technology (ASIS&amp;T) Association of Computing Machinery (ACM) Canadian Students for Sensible Drug Policy (CSSDP)</p>
<h3>Contact</h3>
<p>fergusonrobertdouglas [at] gmail [dot] com</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
